<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Xcode | exit(0);]]></title>
  <link href="http://guidomb.github.io/tech-blog/blog/categories/xcode/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://guidomb.github.io/tech-blog/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-21T16:56:58-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://guidomb.github.io/tech-blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Guido Marucci Blas]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[XCode 6.2 Broke Objective-C's Semantics]]></title>
    <link href="http://guidomb.github.io/tech-blog/blog/2015/03/21/xcode-6-dot-2-broke-objective-c-semantics/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-21T16:01:26-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://guidomb.github.io/tech-blog/blog/2015/03/21/xcode-6-dot-2-broke-objective-c-semantics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yeah the new &ldquo;stable&rdquo; version of XCode is out!!! Version 6.2, we can start hacking for the Apple Watch. The problem is that after installing XCode 6.2 the project I am working on stopped compiling. Without even reading the error message I did the usual thing when a project stops compiling out of the sudden.</p>

<ul>
<li><code>cmd + option + shift + k</code></li>
<li><code>sudo rm -frd /var/folders/*</code></li>
<li><code>rm -frd ~/Library/Developers/Xcode/DerivedData/*</code></li>
</ul>


<p>I did not work so it was time to read the error message:</p>

<pre><code>Use of undeclared identifier '_deviceManager'
</code></pre>

<p>The piece of code that was causing the problem was a simple override of a read only property getter method:</p>

<pre><code class="objc">- (SMODeviceManager *)deviceManager {
  if (_deviceManager == nil) {
    WLXServiceManager * serviceManager = [self managerForServiceWithUUID:SMODeviceManager.serviceUUID];
    _deviceManager = [[SMODeviceManager alloc] initWithServiceManager:serviceManager];
  }
  return _deviceManager;
}
</code></pre>

<p>The actual code in the previous snippet does not matter, it is just lazily initializing an instance variable inside the getter method. What matters is that that piece of code was compiling before I installed XCode 6.2.</p>

<p>After a while I realized that if you declare a property and then
you override a getter or a setter the implicit instance variable
generated by the compiler disappears. I solved this issue by adding <code>@synthesize deviceService = _deviceService;</code>.</p>

<p>What bothers me is that this was something that was working and they broke it in a minor update of the IDE. What is going on with Apple&rsquo;s Q&amp;A? Apple&rsquo;s software does not seem to be as good and as it used to be.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/releasenotes/DeveloperTools/RN-Xcode/Chapters/xc6_release_notes.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40001051-CH4-SW1">release notes</a> do not mention anything related to changing the behavior of properties so I assume that this is a bug. I submitted the issue to Apple and opened a <a href="http://www.openradar.me/radar?id=6753670515392512">radar</a>. In the meantime I am fixing code that used to compile.</p>

<p>Thanks Apple.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
